

# Javad Adib







# Full Stack PHP Developer, Software Engineer

Lives 15+ years with code and debugging as a programmer. Build 7+ infrastructure of multi-million dollar scalable projects from scratch. Earn valuable knowledge via collaboration with specialists. A learner who knows how to learn. Interested in negotiating and comprehending the customer. Extensive wisdom from eCommerce. Open-source enthusiast.

🔀 mr.javad.adib@gmail.com

+98-935-726-9759

Iran

03/202 v6.9.0

2008 - 2014

## **Professional Experience**

### Founder, CEO, and Full Stack Developer

Jibres Iran

(2 years 4 months) 12/2019 - present

- Provide cloud infrastructure to 1,000+ businesses, integrated eCommerce solution with website, app, PoS software, CMS, CRM, accounting software, ticketing system, form builder.
- Joined the bug bounty program and introduced a new WAF that filters and monitors 99% of the attacks.
- Launched an automated app factory that generated a native android shopping app without coding in less than 10 minutes.

## Founder, CEO, and Software Engineer

Ermile Iran

(4 years 7 months) 06/2015 - 12/2019

- Raised \$1M from Angel investor, spearheaded a 15 member cross-functional team to create a Sarshomar that gained about 1M users just a month after launch.
- Constructed an educational management system that serves four organizations, 500,000+ students, 2,000+ teachers.
- Built Siftal UI framework, Dash as PHP framework with MVC pattern, 2x the development speed by consolidated SPA.

#### Web UI/UX Designer

Freelancer

(6 years 10 months) 09/2008 - 06/2015

- Designed, developed 40+ WordPress websites, user experience, communicated with dozens of customers, including universities, companies, celebrities.
- Strengthened negotiation skills, mastered sales skills, optimized speed of 10+ websites, achieved high SEO rank.

### **Computer Lecturer**

**Teacher** 

(15+ years) 06/2006 - (continued)

- Taught 2000+ students in web technologies courses, ICDL in 4 universities, vocational colleges, private classes.
- Created, published tens of hours of unique free web, office video tutorials, which has led to the acquisition of skills by thousands of Persian speakers around the world.

# Volunteer work

#### **DevOps and Front-End Developer**

Khadije Charity Iran (4 years 4 months) 12/2017 - 03/2022

 Developed the website, all the software infrastructure, accelerated fulfill the wishes of 110,000+ people.

#### **Software Solutions for Business Expert**

WorldSkills Iran Iran (5 years 4 months) 06/2010 - 08/2015

 Tutored, train three talents who won silver, two bronze medals in national competitions; Held the national team camp to attend WorldSkills Sao Paulo 2015.

## <u>Languages</u>

English Fluent C1

**Persian** Native

## Education

### M.S. in IT Management

Azad University Tehran, Iran 2015 - 2022

### **B.S. in Computer Software Engineering**

Azad University Nour, Iran

## Skills

Persistence Micro-Management **Analyst** Presentation Accounting Teaching Marketing Sales **Teamwork PWA Decision Making** Microservice Cloud Development **Bug Hunter** Database Design Algorithm Architecture **Data Migration** Maintenance HTML5 IoT **Test Automation** A/B testing Design Pattern pfSense

Fully Proficient Web Technology HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP Language C, C++, C#, VB.NET, Node.js, TypeScript, Python, Bash Data Structure and Database MySQL, SQL Server, JSON, YAML Web Service SOAP, RESTful API, GraphQL

Back-end PHP Web Framework Laravel, Symfony

Frontend JS Library Alpine.js, React, Vue.js, Angular, jQuery

CSS Framework Tailwind, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Materialize

Build Tool Sass, Grunt, Gulp, Gradle, Webpack

Test-driven development - TDD PHPUnit

CI/CD Container Docker, Kubernetes

Backend Web Server Nginx, Apache

Server Configuration Framework, UI cPanel, DirectAdmin Software Development Methodology Scrum, Agile, Kanban OS Windows, Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS, macOS, VMware ESXi Microsoft Office Specialist Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint

Graphic Design Tool Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Figma

## Awards and Honors

MembershipIranNational Elites Foundation2013The Best Corporate, Tourism WebsiteIran5th Iran Web Festival2012Silver MedalYazd, Iran

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Solutions for Business

Medallion for Excellence Mashhad, Iran

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Applications

2008

2009